Finding Aid for the Mae Babitz papers LSC.1740
UCLA Library Special Collections
Mae Babitz papers
circa 1920-2000
UCLA Library Special Collections
Babitz, Mae
LSC.1740
8.5 Linear Feet (17 boxes, 12 oversize boxes, 5 map folders)
Mae Babitz (1911-2003) illustrated architectural landmarks of Los Angeles from 1940 to 1970 and was instrumental in saving Simon Rodia's Watts Towers from destruction. The collection includes artwork as well as personal correspondence and correspondence with the City of Los Angeles with respect to exhibitions, acquisitions and saving the Towers. Babitz is most known for mid-century illustrations of Los Angeles architecture, some of the only surviving records of buildings that no longer exist. Examples include buildings at Bunker Hill, the Bradbury Building, Hollywood Hotel, Watts Towers, and various Victorian homes. A self-trained artist, Babitz used pencil, quill and ink on watercolor paper; she painted at site, primarily of Victorian buildings. After many years of working to get the City of Los Angeles to acquire Babitz's artwork for posterity, her daughter, Mirandi Babitz donated the materials to UCLA in 2006. Collection consists of extensive personal and professional correspondence, personal photographs, loose papers, exhibition fliers and booklets, newspaper and magazine clippings and ephemera of Mae Babitz's life as an artist. In addition to personal and work related papers, the collection includes over 70 illustrations that were shown in galleries and public buildings, and many other earlier sketches and drawings. Also included are correspondence and internal documentation related to and generated by the Committee for Simon Rodia's Towers in Watts.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mirandi Babitz, 2006.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9966032373606533
Biography
Mae Babitz, adventurer, historian, activist, preservationist, artist, wife and mother, was born in Crowley, Louisiana in 1911 to Cajun-French ancestry and baptized Lily May Josephine. Her childhood was spent in the oilfield boomtown, Spindletop, Texas. Babitz moved to Los Angeles in 1934, worked as a secretary and fell in love with Los Angeles architecture. She married musician, Sol Babitz, violinist and consultant to Igor Stravinsky. Igor and Vera Stravinsky became godparents of the Babitz children, Eve and Mirandi. Mae Babitz started a career as an artist in the 1950s as buildings began to be demolished to make way for postwar architecture styles. A self-trained artist, she illustrated primarily Victorian buildings on-site, using pencil, quill and ink on watercolor paper. While some illustrations are in the private collections of the Stravinskys, Edward James and Eugene Berman, most are here at UCLA. Babitz worked with Kate Steinitz and Dr. Elmer Belt in the Elmer Belt Library of Vinciana at UCLA. During that time, Babitz helped found the Committee for Simon Rodia's Towers in Watts in 1959. The Committee lobbied both the City of Los Angeles and private donors and held various fundraisers to successfully save the Watts Towers from destruction. Babitz wrote a biography of Simon Rodia, the research of which included many interviews with Rodia and travelling to his birth place in Italy. The Committee sponsored a documentary film as well. Babitz hosted regular meetings of like-minded artists, poets and musicians, including Igor and Vera Stravinsky, Bernard Herrman, Ingolf Dahl, Kenneth Rexroth, Kenneth Pagent, Jellyroll Morton. She and her husband helped found the Ojai Music Festival.
In the 1960s, Babitz began travelling to Europe with her husband who was awarded Fulbright and Ford Foundation fellowships for European research in baroque musicianship. In these two decades, two major suites of illustrations were completed: "Vanishing Los Angeles" and "The Ancients." Her artwork was showcased in various galleries including Los Angeles County Museum of Art, California Institute of Technology and in private collections of Saul Steinberg, Milton Thomas, Vera Stravinsky, Kate Steinitz and Edward James. Babitz was active in the local arts community, holding memberships in the Los Angeles Art Association, All-City Art Festival, Committee for Simon Rodia's Towers (Founding member, Board member, Archivist), Elmer Belt Library (assistant to Kate Steinitz), Hollywood Arts Council, Beverly Hills Arts League and Friends of the Municipal Gallery. Some of her awards include the California Centennial Exhibition of Art award, Honorable Mention at the All City Art Festival (1957, 1964, 1972) and the Los Angeles cultural Heritage Board Resolution award (1970). Sol, Mae and their daughter, Mirandi, spent many years of working to get the City of Los Angeles to acquire Babitz's artwork for posterity. After all attempts proved fruitless, Mirandi donated the materials to UCLA in 2006. Mae Babitz died in 2003 in Los Angeles.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, personal photographs, loose papers, newspaper and magazine clippings, ephemera of Mae Babitz's life as an artist, Kate Steinitz materials and materials related to the Committee for Simon Rodia's Towers in Watts. Materials in the collection range from the 1920s to the 1990s. In addition to personal and work related papers, the collection includes over 70 illustrations that were shown in local art galleries, banks, art festivals and public buildings, and many other earlier sketches and drawings of Los Angeles and European buildings and scenery. Also included are press releases, price lists and exhibition booklets in which Babitz appears. Personal correspondence includes letters written during Sol and Mae Babitz's travels in Europe, giving a glimpse into postwar Germany and France. Extensive correspondence with her close friend, Edward James, English poet and artist, takes place during his travels in Central America, Mexico and Europe. Periodically James discusses his battle with bipolar disorder as well as local sentiments during the Cold War. Letters occasionally mention the Stravinskys and Peter Yates. There are also photographs and descriptions of James's architectural feats in Xolitil, Mexico. Babitz worked as a secretary for Kate Steinitz, archivist at the Elmer Belt Library of Vinciana at UCLA. The collection includes Kate Steinitz materials consisting of correspondence and many clippings of art, magazines and newspapers. During this time, Babitz cofounded the Committee for Simon Rodia's Towers in Watts. The collection includes correspondence, fliers, interview notes and transcripts and film and audio reels related to Simon Rodia and saving the Towers from destruction.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Mae Babitz Personal Papers
Artwork Documentation and Research Files
Edward James correspondence
Watts Towers
Kate Steinitz materials
Artwork.
Related Material
Information about materials that are not physically or logically included in the material described in the finding aid but that may be of use to a reader because of an association to the described materials.
Sol Babitz Collection of Research Materials, Correspondence, and Papers, 1948-1982. Collection 52, Performing Arts Special Collections, University of California, Los Angeles.
Committee for Simon Rodia's Towers in Watts Records (Collection 1388). UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.
The Elmer Belt Library of Vinciana, UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, University of California, Los Angeles.
Babitz, Mae -- Archives
- 1. Personal Materials, ca. 1940-1990
  Scope and Contents note
  The Personal Materials series includes personal correspondence with friends and family, several letters from Eugene Berman, Russian painter, and photographs of Babitz and her family. There are a few items related to her husband, Sol Babitz.
  - Personal letters, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Personal letters (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal letters, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Personal letters (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Eugene Berman letters, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Mae Babitz and family, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sol Babitz material, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes copy of death certificate, automobile transfer, appearances, obituaries, insurance quote for violin
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes ophthalmology record, 19988 W-2, 1990 Notice of Petition to Administer Estate (Chapman estate), recipes, painted greeting cards, statement on psychological testing, "Louisiana Man" story written by Babitz
- 2. Artwork Documentation and Research Files, ca. 1940-1990
  The Artwork Documentation and Research Files series includes materials related to Babitz's career as an artist. There is extensive correspondence with the city of Los Angeles regarding art exhibitions and acquisitions, newspaper and magazine articles discussing Mae Babitz, price lists of her illustrations, press releases and gallery books and pamphlets. Also included are lists of historical buildings in Los Angeles, photographs and images of buildings and a few small sketches and photographic reproductions of her work.
  - Clippings -- newspaper articles about or mentioning Mae Babitz, ca. 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clippings -- newspaper articles about or mentioning Mae Babitz (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clippings -- other articles mentioning Mae Babitz, ca. 1960-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence -- City of Los Angeles, Cultural Heritage Foundation, ca. 1945-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- grant applications, 1965 and 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- lists of artwork and prices (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- private galleries, ca. 1950-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- press release information, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence -- miscellaneous, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Includes documents related to artist, Yuroz
  - Exhibitions -- pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Exhibitions -- pamphlets, ca. 1950-1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Exhibitions -- miscellaneous, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Title cards for artwork; merit award (1964)
  - Research material -- historical information on Los Angeles and Los Angeles architecture, ca. 1950-1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Research material -- images of buildings, magazine clippings and photocopies, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Research material -- photographs of buildings, primarily Los Angeles architecture, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Research material -- photographic reproductions and photocopies of Babitz's illustrations, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sketches, small pieces of artwork, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Assorted phone numbers, photocopies of magazine advertisements, illustration (artist unknown), art books
  - Oversized -- illustrations, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Oversized -- images of buildings, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
- 3. Edward James Correspondence, ca. 1930-1990
  Edward James, English poet and artist, was a close friend of Mae Babitz and wrote to her often. Most of these letters were written during his travels in Central America, Mexico and Europe. Periodically James discusses his battle with bipolar disorder as well as local sentiments during the Cold War. Letters occasionally mention the Stravinskys and Peter Yates. There are also photographs and descriptions of James's architectural feats in Xolitil, Mexico.
  - Correspondence -- First Husband (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James, 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James (1 of 4), 1980s (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James (2 of 4), 1980s (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James (3 of 4), 1980s (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James (4 of 4) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James (1 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence -- Edward James (2 of 2), undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Hotel stationery, tourist book of Italy, note from Mae Babitz to Evie, receipts
  - Oversized -- Record of a Journey - autobiography and poetry during James's travels, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
- 4. Watts Towers, ca. 1950-2002
  The Watts Tower series includes correspondence to the City of Los Angeles, newsletters, biographical information on Simon Rodia, event fliers, magazine and newspaper clippings, audio and film reels. Letters, newspaper clippings and transcripts of interviews show local and official sentiment of local art and architecture. Included in the collection is an original film reel of a 12-minute documentary, "Simon Rodia and the Towers" (1957), original audio recordings of interviews with Sam Rodia and a biographical manuscript of Rodia written by Mae Babitz.
  - Art books and pamphlets (1 of 3), ca. 1950-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Art books and pamphlets (2 of 3), ca. 1950-1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Art books and pamphlets (3 of 3) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Clippings -- magazines, ca. 1960-1980 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Clippings -- newspapers (1 of 2), ca. 1960-1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Clippings -- newspapers (2 of 2), ca. 1960-1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Committee for Simon Rodia's Towers in Watts (1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Agendas, minutes, project proposals, factsheets
  - Committee for Simon Rodia's Towers in Watts (2 of 2), ca. 1960-1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1959 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1960-1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Includes book project on Rodia's Towers and contract
  - Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence -- miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Notes on the backs of envelopes, list of buildings in San Francisco, mailing list, pages from unknown letters or newsletters
  - Fliers and announcements regarding Towers, ca. 1959-1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters and other written pieces about the Towers (1 of 2), ca. 1950-1980 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters and other written pieces about the Towers (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Photographs and slides (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Research Materials -- hand written notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Research Materials -- notes and narratives (1 of 3), ca. 1950-1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Includes biographical information, interviews, official documents of Sam Rodia and family
  - Research Materials -- notes and narratives (2 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Research Materials -- notes and narratives (3 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Receipts, blank stationery, Watts Towers misc. notes, New Orleans tourist pamphlet, UCLA Jazz flier
  - Media -- 35mm film strip of Watts Towers, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Media -- Film reel -- William Hale architectural film of Watts Towers, approx. 12 minutes, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Media -- VHS -- "Simon Rodia's Watts Towers" (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- Sam Rodia Talks Tape I & II (Wisnieski and Hale), 1953 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- Sam Rodia Talks Tape I & II (Wisnieski and Hale) - duplicate, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- A visit to Sam's Birthplace, ca. 1974 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- KPFK discussion of Towers, approx. 30 min (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- KPFK discussion of Towers, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- Sam IV, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- Cartwright interviewing a film maker, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- Sam I with canton (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- Sam I and II, segments, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- Sam III, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- Watts Towers soundtrack, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Media -- Audio Reel -- Steinitz tape, Schwitters, art (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Media -- calendar, has a page from Towers, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Oversized -- collage and pin art, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Oversized -- Simon Rodia biography, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Oversized -- scrapbook (Box 19, Folder 2)
- 5. Kate Steinitz Materials, ca. 1920-1975
  Steinitz was the archivist for the Elmer Belt Library and an art collector. Having collected da Vinci items, she became a da Vinci scholar and published articles about da Vinci and the collection. This series includes personal correspondence, catalogs of books for sale, clippings and postcards of art work from around the word and journal articles written by Steinitz and others.
  - Catalogs and fliers -- art, ca. 1960-1990 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Catalogs and fliers -- books (1 of 2), ca. 1960-1980 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Catalogs and fliers -- books (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Clippings -- newspaper and magazine articles, ca. 1960-1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Conference fliers, 1950, 1971, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, ca. 1920-1949 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence -- miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- Christmas cards (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Christmas cards, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Postcards to other people, art clippings, list of slides for da Vinci, poetry, mailing labels
  - Correspondence (2 of 2) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Postcards, undated notes, mailing list, letters regarding Kurt Schwitters
  - Correspondence -- newsletters (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Journal Articles -- by Kate Steinitz, ca. 1950-1975 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Journal Articles -- other (1 of 2), ca. 1959-1975 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Journal Articles -- other (2 of 2), ca. 1959-1975 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Postcards -- blank (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Postcards -- blank (2 of 2), undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Photographs of Kate Steinitz, of art work and scenery, of unknown people, of books
  - Miscellaneous -- art clippings (1 of 3) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous -- art clippings (2 of 3) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous -- art clippings (3 of 3), undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous -- other (1 of 2), undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Handwritten notes, airline boarding pass, union meeting booklet, articles on homeopathy and other medical conditions, guitar lesson booklet
  - Miscellaneous -- other (2 of 2), undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Decorative tile, note cards, hand written notes, receipts, clippings of art, card- catalog note cards, gosparlin bridges for string instruments
  - Oversized -- calendar, photo of a dancer, drawing of two babies and copy, flier for da Vinci event, 1972, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Oversized -- letter to Elmer Bert from S. Quiglin, 1949 (Box 30)
  - Mixed media, circular collage wheel by Paul LaPorte, 1964 (Box 34)
  - Oversized -- prints, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
    12 items: prints of Leonardo da Vinci paintings, print of Bernardo Bellato painting, chart of Italian schools, Elmer Belt folder
- 6. Artwork, ca. 1930-1980
  Artwork includes over 70 illustrations that were exhibited and for sale around Los Angeles in galleries and public buildings, as well as many more illustrations and sketches done in Los Angeles and in Europe. Most famous are the illustrations of Victorian era buildings in Los Angeles and her sketches of the Watts Towers and the Bradbury Building.
  - Cathedral, unknown, detail (Germany), 1963 (Box 20)
    Crow quill and ink, and pencil on watercolor paper, 19 1/2" × 15 3/8"
  - Memories of Venice, ca. 1970s (Box 20)
    Crow quill and ink, pencil, and watercolor on watercolor paper, 16" × 22 1/2"
  - The Castle on Bunker Hill, near Grand and Court, 1966-1969 (Box 20)
    Pencil on watercolor paper, 22 1/2" × 30"
  - Berlin Wall, ca. 1960s (Box 20)
    Pencil on watercolor paper, 22" × 30"
  - Worms Cathedral/Cathedral of St. Peter, 1962 (Box 20)
    Pencil on watercolor paper, 19 3/4" × 25 3/4"
  - Brussels Square, 1962 (Box 20)
  - Koln Dom, January 10, 1962 (Box 20)
    Crow quill and ink on watercolor paper, 30 1/4" × 22"
  - Unknown house, Victorian, 1961 (Box 20)
    Crow quill and ink and watercolor on watercolor paper, 22 1/2" × 30 1/2"
  - Old House of Joy, 1953 (Box 20)
    Watercolor on watercolor paper, 20 1/2" × 13"
  - Amestoy Building, Vertical, Main Street near Commercial, site demolished, 1958 (Box 20)
    Crow quill and ink, and pencil on watercolor paper, 30 1/4" × 20 1/4"
  - Italian Scene, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Guanajuato Views, Mexico, 1955 (Box 20)
    Pencil on watercolor paper, 22" × 31"
  - Los Angeles Destruction, site demolished, 1957 (Box 20)
    Crow quill and ink, and pencil on watercolor paper, 22 1/2" × 30 3/4"
  - Rathius Gouda (Rathaus), 1962-1963 (Box 20)
    Crow quill and ink on watercolor paper, 27' × 21 3/4"
  - Speyer Cathedral (Box 20)
    Pencil on watercolor paper, 25 3/4" × 19 1/2"
  - Cathedral (Rouen), 1963 (Box 20)
    Crow quill and ink, watercolor, and gouache on watercolor paper, 22" × 30"
  - Bradbury Building Memories, 3rd and Broadway, Cultural Heritage, 1967-1968 (Box 20)
    Silkscreen collage with cut-out sheet music on watercolor paper laid down, 30 3/4" × 22 1/2"
  - Pueblo, 1954 (Box 20)
  - Reims Cathedral, 1963 (Box 20)
    Ink on paper, 10 1/2" × 8 1/4"
  - Tubingen, 1962 (Box 20)
  - Rouen Cathedral, 1963-1968 (Box 20)
    Watercolor and pencil on watercolor paper, 22" × 30#
  - Daisy Baird House on Hope Street, site demolished, 1957 (Box 21)
    Crow quill and ink, watercolor, and gouache on watercolor paper, 30" × 40"
  - Koln Dom, detail (Box 21)
    Pencil on watercolor paper, 31" × 22 1/4"
  - Bradbury Building Memories, 3rd and Broadway, Cultural Heritage, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
  - Assisi, 1972 (Box 21)
    Watercolor and pencil on watercolor paper, 27 1/2" × 39 1/2"
  - L.A. Main Street Lugo House (China Town), site demolished, 1953-1959 (Box 22)
    Oil on canvas, in frame, 20" × 24"
  - Dead Wino, Skid Row, 1955 (Box 23)
    Crow quill and ink, and gouache on watercolor paper, 22 1/2" × 27"
  - Bunker Hill Street House, site demolished, 1953 (Box 23)
  - Pisa, 1975 (Box 23)
    Pencil and watercolor on watercolor paper, 22" × 30"
  - The Towers of Simon Rodia, 107th St., 1959 (Box 23)
    Watercolor and print on watercolor paper, 19 3/4" × 27 3/4"
  - Tours St. Gatien (Box 23)
    Pencil and watercolor on watercolor paper
  - Plaza Mission, 1950 (Box 23)
    Crow quill and ink, and pencil on watercolor paper, 22" × 30"
  - Los Angeles High School, Wooden House, site demolished, 1949-1950 (Box 23)
    Crow quill and ink, and pencil on watercolor paper, 20" × 29"
  - Hale House, 4571 N. Figueroa Street, Cultural Heritage (currently located at Heritage Square), 1958 (Box 23)
    Pencil on watercolor paper, 22 1/2" × 30 3/4"
  - Fagan Phantasy, view of Main Street, site demolished, 1956 (Box 23)
    Crow quill and ink, and pencil on watercolor paper, 21 1/2" × 21 1/2"
  - Demolition at 4th and Main Street (Cleveland Wrecking Company), site demolished, 1960 (Box 23)
    Pencil on watercolor paper, 20 1/4" × 30 1/4"
  - Watts Towers, 107th at Wilmington, 1959 (Box 23)
    Watercolor and collage print on watercolor paper, 19 3/4" × 27 3/4"
  - Condemned Building, 1951 (Box 23)